powerledger.io 2019-12-09

# Privacy Policy - Power Ledger

Your privacy is very important to us at Power Ledger, and so is being transparent about the types of data we collect about you when you use our website or services, or interact with us in any other way. This policy is here to help you understand how we collect, use, share and protect any personal information we gather about you. It is also clear about the choices you have over how we process your data, including how you can access or request any changes to the information we have about you.

Please read the following policy carefully. If you do not agree with any aspect of this policy, please do not continue to use our website or any of our other services. By continuing to use our website or services after 14 August 2018, you acknowledge our updated Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

## Types of information we collect about you

When you use our website, or interact with us through our services, there are certain types of information we may collect from you along the way.

Information you provide to us directly: We collect information about you when you provide it to us voluntarily. This could be when you subscribe to our newsletter, send us correspondence, contact us through our various website forms or otherwise provide it directly to us. This type of information includes but is not limited to:

  * First and last name
  * Email address
  * Location details – e.g. country, city or town of residence
  * Phone number
  * Professional details – e.g. information provided in the process of proposing potential projects
  * Experience – including employment and personal experience relevant to any job application you submit to us
  * Other information you provide through our support channels

Information we collect when you use the Power Ledger platform: If you are a customer using the Power Ledger trading platform, or any of our other platform services, we may collect the following information about you:

  * Account and profile information;
  * Information about the premises (i.e. whether residential or commercial); and
  * Metering data

This information is used to provide the platform services you have signed up for, and is handled in compliance with relevant legislation and/or legal agreements.

Information we collect from you automatically when you use our services: When you interact with our website or other services, we may receive and store certain information automatically. This includes technical data your browser sends when you use a website – such as IP address, browser type and version, device ID, time zone setting and location.

### **Third party analytics**

We use third party analytics tools, including HubSpot Analytics and Google Analytics, to collect certain information about your visits to our website and services. These tools help us keep a record of information, including the pages our users access, the documents they download, links from other sites they follow to reach the Power Ledger site, and the type of browser they use. These types of information help us improve our services, and is generally only used for statistical and website development purposes. We may store this type of information or it may be included in databases owned and maintained by affiliates or service providers. You can find out more information about Google analytics [here](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.&sa=D&ust=1534491647854000).

## How we use cookies

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on your computer, phone or tablet when you visit a website. Our website uses cookies to collect information about a range of user activities on the site.

Why do we use cookies? We use cookies to tell you apart from other visitors to the site, and to make improvements to both the site and our range of other services. We use cookies to accurately measure usage sessions and gain a clear picture of the areas of the site which attract the most traffic. We also use cookies to improve the functionality of our website. For example, if we provide a notice or update regarding a significant change to the law, we use cookies to make sure you don’t see this notice each time you access a different page on our website.

### Types of cookies

  * Session cookies – these expire when the browser is closed.
  * Permanent cookies – these are stored on your computer after you close your browser until their expiration date, or until you delete them.
  * Third-party cookies – these are placed on your browser by websites other the one you are on.

Our web analytics providers (HubSpot and Google Analytics) implement cookies to gather information about our website users, for the purposes outlined above.

### Main cookies used by Power Ledger

Cookie Name | Purpose  
---|---  
__hstc (expires: 2 years) 

__hssc (expires: 30 mins)

Hubspotutk (expires: 10 years)

| HubSpot Marketing and communications tracking – help keep track of visitor identity and sessions  
__ga (expires: 2 years) 

__utma (expires: 2 years)

__utmb (expires: 30 mins)

__utmc (session cookie)

__utmz (expires: 6 months)

| Google analytics tracking – collects information such as pages visited and time spent viewing pages  
  
### How to turn cookies off

If you don’t want us to use cookies, you can change and manage your preferences through your browser settings (privacy and security control settings). Please keep in mind that turning cookies off may restrict access to parts of the site and will impact your overall experience – we recommend you leave them on.

To find out more about cookies, including how to manage or opt-out of our use of cookies, please click [here](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.allaboutcookies.org/&sa=D&ust=1534491647859000). If you continue to use the site you consent to our use of cookies.

## How we use information we collect about you

How we use the information we collect about you will depend on which Power Ledger services you are using, as well as the preferences you have selected during your engagement with these services.

The information we collect about you is processed by us, or by third party affiliates, who have an equivalent or stronger privacy regime to that described in this policy. We use your information for the following types of purposes:

  * To provide you with services and personalize your experience on the site;
  * To communicate effectively with you or provide you with specialized customer support services;
  * To help us identify areas of the site and our services that require improvement or added efficiencies;
  * To communicate with you about new project announcements, events or new service or product offerings;
  * To help direct our marketing, promote our services and drive engagement with our platform and services;
  * To help make improvements and administer the website; or
  * To inform you of general Power Ledger news updates (if you have provided your consent for us to do so).

Legal bases for processing (for EEA users): If you are an individual currently located in the European Economic Area (EEA), Power Ledger is the ‘data controller’ of your personal information under applicable EU law. We collect and process information about you only where we have the legal basis for doing so. This legal basis will depend on which part of our website or services you use, and how you use them.

This means we collect and use your information only where:

  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest, such as for research and development or delivering the platform or services (but only if your rights and obligations do not override the legitimate interest);
  * We need to process your data to comply with our legal obligations

If you have consented to our use of your information you have the right to change your mind at any time, although please keep in mind this will not affect any processing that’s already taken place.

## How we share any information we collect about you

We will only share your personal information with third parties in the following types of circumstances:

  * Within Power Ledger itself – e.g. in order to improve the website or deliver the services;
  * With one of our trusted third party service providers to fulfil any of the purposes listed above, and only in accordance with our instructions; or
  * When you have given us your consent to do so.

We may share your information with trusted third party service providers in order to deliver the services you have signed up for, or to market additional services to you. Please be aware that some of these providers may receive or store your information in an overseas jurisdiction. We will not sell your information to any third parties or advertisers, including for marketing purposes.

### Legal obligations

We may disclose relevant information with courts or law enforcement authorities if we are legally compelled to do so. We may also use this information to defend or exercise our legal rights.

### Links to other websites

Our website provides links to other websites, including Twitter, Medium, Facebook, LinkedIn and Reddit. These other sites are not controlled or operated by us, and we are not responsible for their content or practices. The procedures and policies described in this privacy policy do not apply to these other websites. Third party websites may place their own cookies on your browser, or store information about you in accordance with different methods to those used by Power Ledger. These sites are subject to any privacy or cookie policies they have in place, and we encourage you to to read these carefully.

You should note that these external links are placed on the site in a format which allows us to track the number of people following the links.

## Where we store your information

We collect information from wherever you are located around the globe, and will primarily store that information on servers located and operated in Australia. This means we may transfer, process and store your information outside of your country of residence, to wherever we, or our third-party service providers operate. We take steps to protect any data we transfer. Any personal information about you that we collect and use, will be subject to the data privacy laws in place in Australia. These laws will be different, and in some cases less protective than those that apply to you in your country of residence.

By accepting the terms of this privacy policy, and continuing to use our site (or otherwise providing your personal information) you acknowledge and consent to the processing and transfer of your information outside of your country of residence as described in this policy. You also understand that the data protection laws of Australia may not be as comprehensive or protective as the laws of the country in which you live, and there is a risk in using the website and our services.

## How we keep the information we collect secure

Power Ledger takes the security of your personal information very seriously. We take all possible steps to help protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Any personal data is secured on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment using appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures. Where your personal information flows through our trusted third party service providers, we cannot guarantee the security measures they may employ.

While we do implement appropriate safeguards, no security system is impenetrable. Due to the inherent nature of the internet, we cannot guarantee that data is absolutely safe from third party interference, either during transmission or during the time it is stored on our systems.

### Data breaches

We have established procedures to detect any real or suspected data breaches and act in accordance with legal obligations. In the event of a breach, we have dedicated response plans which outline the requisite engagement with regulatory bodies, and the circumstances in which we will need to notify you (in the event your personal information is impacted).

### Storage of data

We only collect personal information that is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, and will only store this data for a period of time reasonably necessary to provide the services (or the period set by relevant legal provisions).

## How to access and control your personal information

As a user of our website or other services, you have certain rights available which give you more control over how we process and use your personal information. The following are some of these rights:

  * You can request access to your personal information and be informed
  * You can request to have your information corrected or updated if it is found to be inaccurate;
  * If you gave us your consent to process your data, you can withdraw your consent at any time (this will not affect any processing that has already taken place);
  * You can request that we delete your data under certain circumstances;
  * You can restrict us from processing certain personal information
  * You can request to have your data transferred to another organisation
  * You can object to our use of your information, including for marketing purposes

If we are not able to fully comply with your request, we will always tell you the reasons why. For example, we may not be able to fulfil your request if you ask for the deletion of information in which we have a legitimate interest, or the deletion of information we need to keep in order to fulfil our legal obligations. To exercise any of these rights or make a complaint you can contact us using the contact details at the bottom of this privacy policy.

## Complaints

Under certain circumstances, you can make a complaint about the way we handle data to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, using the process outlined  
[here](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.oaic.gov.au/individuals/how-do-i-make-a-privacy-complaint&sa=D&ust=1534491647869000). If you are an EEA resident, you can make a complaint to the relevant Data Protection Authority, which can be found [here](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm&sa=D&ust=1534491647869000).

## Opting out of communications

You can always unsubscribe from any of our marketing or service communications by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails, by updating your preferences, or by sending us an email at [support@powerledger.io](mailto:support@powerledger.io). Remember you can also unsubscribe from any unwanted communications with third parties using the same processes.

## Other important information

### Changes to this privacy policy

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted on the website and if the changes are significant, we will provide you with more prominent notice of this (most likely through an email notification or a banner on the site). While you will be notified of any material changes, we also encourage you to check our website periodically to ensure that you are aware of Power Ledger’s current privacy policy.

### Our policy towards children

Our website and services are aimed at general audiences, and are not directed at anyone under the age of 16. If it is brought to our attention that we have collected the personal information of someone under the age of 16, we will take every effort to delete it from our databases as soon as possible.

## How to contact us

If you have any more questions about this privacy policy, or would like more information about how Power Ledger Pty Ltd handles your information, please contact us at support@powerledger.io or on +618 9322 6659

If you do not agree with the data practices outlined in this Privacy Policy, you should not use the website or interact with any other aspect of our business.

Power Ledger  
‘The Palace’, Level 2 108 St Georges Tce  
Perth 6000  
WESTERN AUSTRALIA  
ABN: 39 612 531 218  
TEL: +618 9322 6659
